imagine this diagram with two squares 1
1 4 the size of the other encloses a
total area of one now cut both squares
into four equal pieces and remove one
this removes a total of one-fourth of
the area of the diagram on the removed
area cut that into four pieces and
re-add one piece thus adding one-fourth
of one-fourth back we can imagine
repeating this process indefinitely each
time removing one quarter of the area
and then re-adding one quarter of that
removed area back if we do this
infinitely then the resulting limiting
diagram has a shaded area given by the
infinite sum of the powers of negative
one-fourth and now here's the trick we
can shift the Shaded part of the small
square up to the larger Square thus
filling in all of the larger square but
by construction the larger Square was
four times bigger than the small square
and therefore we've shaded exactly
four-fifths of the original area this
means the sum of the powers of negative
one fourth is four-fifths